# Jason Sonderman, UXC

iason.sonderman.info 3816.522.9954

in linkedin.com/in/jasonsonderman

### Summary

I improve users' lives through sound user experience strategies. For the last 3 years, this focus has been on the higher education seeker looking for online degree opportunities. Prior to that, it was 3 years focusing on the medical professional looking to understand the new digital world of caring for people.

Bringing creative leadership to projects, I solve problems through user-centered design and design thinking practices. I relentlessly collaborate and explore, inviting all who want to join in the discovery. My rich professional experience allows me to bridge the worlds of user experience and technology.

Leading through servant leadership practices, I have united and grown teams on the opposite sides of the globe. I have made space for my team to take up leadership roles in process improvement and defining engaging experiences. Together, we have launched more than 30 websites, 40 landing pages, and 2 large-scale learning platforms.

#### Experience

#### Lead UX Developer

**Archer Education** 

Jul 2018 - Present

At Archer, I collaborate and direct the creation of compelling, informative experiences for online higher ed seekers to promote trust and commitment for our education partners through the practice of user research, UX principles, design thinking, and the direction of multidiscipline teams.

My primary responsibilities are:

- Translate business needs into requirements for UX, Design, and Web Development
- Optimize the information architecture to promote usability, while accommodating technical
- needs/constraints
- Prioritize roadmap features and product enhancement requests, specifically around UX
- Establish a sound UX strategy that meets the user needs and achieves the business goals •
- Develop journey maps, information architectures, and wireframes to articulate the UX strategy

The primary achievements at Archer are:

- Implement User Experience processes across the organization to build awareness and establish value to the business
- Establish the foundation of a User Experience team through the articulation of the vision to our executive leadership
- Develop sustainable, repeatable processes for launching websites
- Advocate for our end-user in the discovery and creative phases of projects
- Manage the creation and maintenance of the organizational component design system by applying the findings from usability research to the elements and patterns that are used throughout our web-facing products (landing pages, microsites, websites, etc).

#### Lead Strategist/Practice Manager - eLearning

**Cerner Corporation** 

#### Dec 2015 - Jun 2018

Cerner Learning Services engages with clients to develop and deliver meaningful and impactful learning strategies that enable end-users to adapt to changes in the healthcare space. During my tenure as the Practice Manager, I was responsible for aligning the overall business unit to increase our value to our clients through predictable, high-quality releases of tools and engaged services as well as casting the vision of online learning by integrating the needs of the broader business with input from my team leads.

Key achievements at Cerner in this role were:

- Grow the business unit from two distinct teams (US & India) of 38 team members into a unified business operation of 70 team members worldwide.
- Establish an 18-hour work process to maximize the time difference between the team, as well as implement a 5-week AGILE development and testing cycle.
- Successfully lead the building, deploying, and packaging of a performance-based learning application for sale to our medical professional client base.

## Principal UX Architect & Web Developer/Partner

blue148, inc

Jan 2003 - Dec 2015

Co-founder of a web design business, specializing in graphic design and website development.

Throughout the 13 years of operations, I lead the effort to gain new clients and deliver stellar web and UI design work to meet the needs of the end-user and the client's goals. I led the implementation of a customizable CMS to manage the sites we built and maintained to maximize our efficiency to go live for a variety of clients.

The business had 30 clients of record who regularly used our design and development services for e-commerce website builds, email campaigns, and delivery of previously printed content through online technologies.

Our clients ranged from large-scale international manufacturers to small start-up service companies.

For a complete history of my professional experience, please visit my LinkedIn Profile: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jasonsonderman/details/experience/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/jasonsonderman/details/experience/</a>

#### Education

Nielsen Norman Group - User Experience Certification (UXC)

Kansas City Art Institute - BFA, Graphic Design & Printmaking